The Perfect Neighbor is a documentary, thriller,
crime film directed by Geeta Gandbhir.
Police bodycam footage reveals how a long-running neighborhood dispute turned fatal
in this documentary about fear, prejudice and Stand Your Ground laws.
Self (archive footage), played by Susan Lorincz.
Self (archive footage), played by Ajike Owens.
Self (archive footage), played by Pamela Dias.
The Perfect Neighbor is a 2025 American documentary film directed by Geeta Gandbhir about the killing of Ajike Owens, a shooting incident on
June 2, 2023 where a white female, Susan Louise Lorincz, fatally shot Owens, her black female neighbor, in Ocala, Florida.
The film is told in chronological order with limited narration, mostly using pre-existing police footage such as bodycams', and follows both the lead-up to the killing, the
incident itself and its aftermath, from the neighborhood disputes eventually escalating into the killing to Lorincz's conviction for manslaughter, among other charges.
As the killing itself did, the film notably questions the systemic bias
in how Florida's stand-your-ground laws are applied.
The film had its world premiere at the 2025 Sundance Film Festival
on January 24, where it won the Directing Award.
It had a limited theatrical release in the U.S.
on October 10, prior to streaming globally on Netflix on October 17.
It received widespread acclaim for its production, direction and editing, and its effective
questioning of the circumstances surrounding Owens' death and similar incidents.
At the 98th Academy Awards, it was nominated for Best Documentary.
The film explores themes of florida, based on true story,
neighborhood watch, neighborhood, woman director.
The tone is intense.